Long live the king.
Godzilla: King of the Monsters is a science fiction,
action film directed by Michael Dougherty.
Follows the heroic efforts of the crypto-zoological agency Monarch as its members face off against a battery of god-sized monsters,
including the mighty Godzilla, who collides with Mothra, Rodan, and his ultimate nemesis, the three-headed King Ghidorah.
When these ancient super-species, thought to be mere myths, rise again, they all vie
for supremacy, leaving humanity's very existence hanging in the balance.
Mark Russell, played by Kyle Chandler.
Emma Russell, played by Vera Farmiga.
Madison Russell, played by Millie Bobby Brown.
Dr. Ishiro Serizawa, played by Ken Watanabe.
Dr. Ilene Chen / Dr. Ling, played by Zhang Ziyi.
Dr. Rick Stanton, played by Bradley Whitford.
Godzilla: King of the Monsters is a 2019 American monster film produced
by Legendary Pictures and distributed by Warner Bros.
Co-written and directed by Michael Dougherty, it is a sequel to
Godzilla (2014) and the third film in the Monsterverse.
It is also the 35th film in the Godzilla franchise, and the third
Godzilla film to be completely produced by a Hollywood studio.
The film stars Kyle Chandler, Vera Farmiga, Millie Bobby Brown, Bradley Whitford, Sally Hawkins, Charles Dance,
Thomas Middleditch, Aisha Hinds, O'Shea Jackson Jr., David Strathairn, Ken Watanabe, and Zhang Ziyi.
In the film, eco-terrorists release King Ghidorah, who awakens other monsters known as "Titans" across the
world, forcing Godzilla and Mothra to surface and engage Ghidorah and Rodan in a decisive battle.
The sequel was greenlit during the opening weekend of Godzilla, with
Gareth Edwards expected to return to direct a trilogy.
In May 2016, Edwards left the project.
In October 2016, Dougherty and Shields were hired to rewrite the script.
In January 2017, Dougherty was announced as the director.
Principal photography began in June 2017 in Atlanta,
Georgia, and wrapped in September 2017.
The film is dedicated to executive producer
Yoshimitsu Banno (director of Godzilla vs.
Hedorah) and original Godzilla suit performer Haruo
Nakajima, both of whom died in 2017.
Godzilla: King of the Monsters was theatrically released on May 31, 2019, to mixed reviews from critics, with praise for its visual
effects, action sequences, cinematography, and musical score but with criticism to the plot, pacing, tone and characters.
The film was a box office disappointment, grossing $387.3 million worldwide against a production budget of $170–200
million and marketing costs of $100–150 million, marking it the lowest-grossing film in the Monsterverse.
A sequel, Godzilla vs.
Kong, was released on March 24, 2021.
The film explores themes of mexico, boston, massachusetts,
giant monster, cryptozoology, eco terrorism.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.